## The Resume of

#### MD TAMZID HASAN

North South University Bashundhara R/A Dhaka- 1229, Bangladesh thunique1988@gmail.com +880 1711 927924 Portfolio: www.tamzid.info



#### **Objective**

To build up a career in the technical field, concentrating on research and development in order to boost production. My integrity and devotion to work motivated me to learn and share knowledge within the team, where multitasking, strong leadership, and interpersonal communication skills are most important.

#### **Experience**

Jhpiego Bangladesh

Project on Maternal Immunization Readiness Initiative.

Consultant

January 2023 to February 2024

Jhpiego Bangladesh

NSU Global Health Institute

Develop a Health Facility Readiness Assessment Tool (HFRA)

for Maternal Immunization (MI).

Contributor

March 2023 to January 2024

Department of Public Health, North South University Myopia and dry-eye disease among the female students of NSU.

NSU Global Health Institute
People's perception, experience, and usage of health facilities.

Qualitative Data Collector
November 2023

NSU Global Health Institute USAID's Community-Health-Systems Strengthening Activity

(CHSS).

Department of Public Health, North South University PTSD, Insomnia, and Suicidal Ideation among the firefighters of Bangladesh.

North South University

Department of Public Health, School of Health & Life Science

North South University

Chalmers University of Technology High Voltage Converter Transformer using Non-destructive Methods.

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology Performance Analysis of Boost Inverter for using in PV system.

S. S. Engineering & Construction Builders, developers, & construction.

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

Project Work September 2023

Research Assistant

October 2023

Thesis Work

November 2023

Research Assistant August 2022 to December 2023

Graduate Teaching Assistant June 2022 to January 2023

> Project Work October 2018

Thesis Work June 2018

Electrical Engineer October 2013 to July 2017











GS Engineering & Construction

Bibiyana to Kaliakoir 400KV overhead transmission line supervised by PGCB.

Supervision of Project April 2013 to August 2013

GS Engineering & Construction Engineering & Construction

Electrical Engineer April 2013 to August 2013

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Designing & Installation of 10 kWp solar system with 3 hrs battery backup at MCC, Mymensingh.

Project Monitoring May 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Installation of 2.55 kWp solar system with 4 hrs battery backup at ARC Architect, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Project Monitoring March 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Installation of 1.2 kWp solar system with 2 hrs battery backup at Jafrabad, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Project Monitoring February 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd Renewable energy system Assistant Engineer November 2011 to July 2012

#### **Education**

MPH in Epidemiology
Masters in EPE
Chalmers University of Technology
On hold
BSc in EEE
Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology
2021 – 2022
On hold
2006 – 2011

### **Honors & Scholarships**

University scholarship for MPH program

International student scholarship for master's program in Sweden

Scholarship awarded to attend the study session of Peace in the Spotlight in Strasbourg, France.

Scholarship awarded to attend the project management training in the frame of Peers to Peace in Athens, Greece. North South University Adlerbert Foreign Student Hospitality Foundation

Council of Europe

Erasmus+ Scholarship

#### Skills

Skills are developed by professional and academic work. And good collaboration with EPI, MNC&AH, DGHS, MoHFW, Bangladesh, and other international organisations.

#### **Research Skills**

- Conduct study, proposal writing, study design, sample estimation.
- Monitoring & Evaluation the project or program.
- Grand proposal writing for the fund and development of the project.
- Transcription and translation of IDIs, KIIs, and FGDs.

#### **Development Skills**

- ◆ Develop a Health Facility Readiness Assessment Tool for Maternal Immunization in Bangladesh.
- Assist faculty members in the preparation of different module development.
- Prepare reports and design specifications, conduct research, and supervised the team.

### **Coordinating Skills**

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info











- ♦ Assist faculty members with classroom instruction, exams, record keeping, and other miscellaneous projects and develop course plans.
- Assist academic staff with the development or update of learning materials, proctor exams, and record grades in the grade book.
- Survey the site and manage the design and construction of electrical systems.

### **Training Skills**

- Tutor or mentor students in class or outside.
- Prepare reports and design specifications, conduct research, and training.
- Supervised and trained project team members.

#### **Computer Skills**

- Data analysis and visualization with R, Rstudio, and STATA.
- End Note, Zotero, and Mendely for reference management.
- MS Office (Word, Excel, and Powerpoint) & LaTEX writing tools.

### **Scientific Work**

#### **Journal Publication**

Md. Shafiqul Islam, Syed Muhammad Baqui Billah, Jewell Ilias Rab, Abir Dey, Md. Habib Naziat, and Md. Tamzid Hasan (2024): Prevalence of Diabetic Retinopathy and Associated Risk Factors in the Southern Region of Bangladesh. International Journal of Human and Health Sciences. DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.31344/ijhhs.v8i2.640

Azaz Bin Sharif, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Syed Sharaf Ahmed Chowdhury, and Satyajit Kundu (2023): *Inequalities in early initiation of breastfeeding in Bangladesh: An estimation of relative and absolute measures of inequality.* International Breastfeeding Journal. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s13006-023-00584-y">https://doi.org/10.1186/s13006-023-00584-y</a>

Azaz Bin Sharif, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Md. Habib Naziat, Tahmina Zerin, and Satyajit Kundu (2023): *Permanent, long-acting, and short-acting reversible contraceptive methods use among women in Bangladesh: An analysis of Bangladesh Demographic and Health Survey 2017-2018 data.* BMJ Open 2023;13:e073469. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2023-073469

Md Jakaria Rahimi, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Ripan Kumar Dhar, Md Shaheer Ibne Islam, Khatune Jannat Siddiqua, and Shahriar Azgar (2011): *Performance Analysis of Boost Inverter for Photovoltaic System*. IJETSE International Journal of Emerging Technologies in Science and Engineering, Vol.5, No.2, Dec 2011.

## **Skills Development Work**

#### **Training & Workshops**

A training on 'Mastering Monitoring, Evaluation, Accountability, Learning-Transferring Knowledge into Practice.'

Department of Public Health,

DHS capacity building workshop on 'Using the DHS Dataset into Research' proposed by USAID.

Global Health Institute, NSU

MEAL Perspective Hub

A training on 'Scientific Writing' organized by School of Health & Life Science, North South University.

Workshop on 'How to develop an analytical plan for a research project- the gateway of writing a manuscript' organized by The Global Health Network Asia.

icddr'b

A training on 'Peace in the Spotlight' organized by SCI & VYRE.

Council of Europe











Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

A training on 'Project management in the frame of the Peers to Peace' co-funded by the Europe for Citizens Program of the EU.

SCI

## **Volunteering Work**

## **Major Activities**

CERIA Farm International Work Camp in Ipoh, Perak at Malaysia.	SCI Malaysia
International Work Camp IN-SCI 11.10 on Achalam Eco ashram- From Ego	SCI India &
to Eco (EE01) in Tiruvannamalai, Tamil Nadu at India.	SCI Hong Kong
International Work Camp NP-SCI 13.4 on Help in Reconstruction of School	SCI Nanal
Building in Balthali, Panauti at Nepal.	SCI Nepal
International Work Camp BD-SCI 11.5 on Climate & Sustainable	CCI Domaladash
Lifestyle with River Erosion Affected Community in Shibchar, Madaripur.	SCI Bangladesh

## Membership

Member of Public Health Association of Bangladesh (PHAB).	2022
Member of Public Health and Science Club, North South University.	2021
Vice President of ANIMESH a social organization.	2021
Reception Host- 2018 of Chalmers Studentkårs Arbetsmarknardsdagar (CHARM),	2018
Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden.	
Member of The Institution of Engineers, Bangladesh (IEB). Memership No. M/34701.	2012
Volunteer Coordinator of Service Civil International- Bangladesh (SCI-BD).	2015
Member of Service Civil International- Bangladesh (SCI-BD).	2007

# Referees

Available upon request.

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info









